Nicholas Howard

nhowar@uwo.ca ❖ (581) 922-3342 ❖ London, ON

Objective

Creative and diligent computer science student with well developed technical proficiency that builds upon six years of managerial experience in the reclamation industry. I am eager to apply my technical skills and well as teamwork and problem solving abilities to projects in software development.

Education

University of Western Ontario 2021-present Honors Specialization in Computer Science. London, Ontario

- Dean's Honor List 2021, 2022, & 2023
- Maintained an average of 88%

Technical Skills

- Object Oriented Programming in Python, Java, and C with particular proficiency in
- MySQL & Database Management
- Linux Bash and package management
- HTML & CSS
- GitHub and Version Control
- Jira, Confluence
- ,

Projects

- LogicLand An educational app that teaches formal logic and foundational computer science concepts through the use of logic gates. Completed as a group project for Western in which I was responsible for the user interface and collaborated with another member on the logic circuits. Programmed in Java using JavaFX.
 - A demonstration can be found here https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5IKi6Te4YFs
 - The code can be found here https://github.com/readygroup1/LogicLand

Soft Skills

Leadership

As a Manager at Little Smokey, I was responsible for hiring, training and daily management of a crew of up to eleven planters in the reforestation of previously logged land in Northern Alberta. Each summer my crew and I would plant approximately a million trees and reclaim over 700 hectares of land.

Analytical Thinking and Logistics

At Little Smokey, I planned and executed daily deliveries of tens of thousands of seedlings by various means such as ATV and via helicopter. I would analyze the map to ensure that the correct tree species was planted into the correct type of land for each of my planters.

Work Experience

- Little Smokey Forestry Services Foreman Grande Prairie, AB May 2017 August 2022 Whistler Blackcomb September 2016 -May 2017 Logistics associate Whistler, BC
- Gentech Roofing August 2015 September 2016 Labourer Mississauga, ON
- Summit Screen Printing Supplies October 2013—August 2015 Penticton, BC Assisted in the purchase, relocation, and modernization of a distribution business.